Help！
救命！
Eddie！
爱迪！
Eddie，wake up
爱迪！醒醒！
- Don't move。Okay，listen to me。- Where are we？
- 不要动！听我说！ - 这是哪儿啊？
- Whatever you do，don't lean forward。- What's this？What's…
- 不管怎样都别站起来！ - 这咋的了这是？
- What's going on？- No！
- 怎么一回事？ - 别动！！
Hello。I want to play a game.
两位好，我想玩个游戏
The devices on your heads are symbolic of the shackles that you place upon others.
你们头上的机关，是一种象征，象征着无良放贷者 桎梏贷款者的罪行
You recklessly loan people money，knowing their financial limitations，
明知他们的经济状况，你们仍发放贷款
counting on repossessing more than they could ever pay back.
硬逼借款者偿还高额利息
You are predators，but today，you become the prey.
你们这两个食肉者，今天将成为献肉者
And it is your own pound of flesh that I demand.
我要你们献出一定份量的肉块
This is your fault！
这都怪你！
The scale before you is your only path to freedom.
面前天秤，自由之门
However，only one of you may pass，
人数有限，两人争先
and the toll is the ultimate sacrifice，
通关代价：终极天罚
the sacrifice of flesh.
切割砍剁，牺牲鲜肉
Before you are the instruments to exact this flesh.
面前仪器，传送献祭
Move with haste，though，
一分钟内
for when the 60- second timer hits zero，
重量比对
the one who has given the most flesh will release their bindings，
重者获胜，轻者失败
while the gears on your opponent's head will engage，piercing their skull.
败者下场，穿脑而亡
Who will offer the most flesh in order to save their life？
是生是死，自己选择
The choice is yours.
谋事在我，成事在人
No！
不！
I'm not dying for you，bitch！
我才不会坐以待毙，婊子！
No！
不！
《电锯惊魂6》
I ask you，Special Agent Strahm，
我说，斯特拉姆探员
have you learned enough to trust me？
你学会相信我了么
For if you do not，this room will forever be your tomb.
不过，如果选择不进去，那你就将长眠于此
You will never be heard from again，your body will never be found，
你将人间蒸发，生不见人，死不见尸
and my legacy will become yours.
而我的黑锅，就由你来替我背着
Make your choice.
做出抉择吧
There was a pre- existing condition，
有个之前就存在的问题
which you did not inform your insurance company of.
您没有事先通知保险公司
Thank you.
谢谢
Hey，babe。Good。Listen，I am so，so sorry，but I can't make dinner.
嘿亲爱的，好的，可是，非常非常抱歉 不用喊我回家吃饭了
I've got to work late again。I have a meeting with my lawyer
单位有事，要见我的律师
this will keep me busy for the rest of the afternoon.
忙好估计很晚了
I know it's your birthday，and I'll make it up to you。I promise
我知道今天是你的生日，我会补的，放心吧
Love you.
我爱你
- Uh，what were we talking about？- We're talking about your deposition.
- 额…刚才说到哪了？ - 说到你的证词
So worried about me，Debbie
别那么担心，黛比
Some small- time lawyer trying to squeeze us
在那种菜B律师面前，
is not going to get me to say anything I don't want to say.
我不会说漏嘴的
I have no doubt about that，
这我知道
but as lead counsel for this company，if you screw up，it comes down on my ass.
但作为公司首席律师，你要是搞砸了，我也会跟着挨板子
So what do you say we prep your deposition？
所以呢，你的证词，准备得怎样了？
Oh，Christ.
唉…顶你条粉肠
Do you remember dealing with a Mr。Harold Abbott？
你还记得哈罗德·阿贝特先生的事吗？
William，I have a Casey Patterson on Line One.
威总，凯西·帕特森找您，一号线
Take another message，Addy，I'll get back to her this week
让她留言，阿蒂嫂，我这周会打给她的
Sometime…Keep going
如果我有空的话…你继续
When opposing counsel asks about Mr。Abbot，how will you respond？
假如对方律师问起来，你怎么回答？
I am going to respond by saying：
我会这么回复：
As Senior Vice President of Membership and Claims，
作为这家公司客户索赔部的副主管
it is my job to review to review every terminated policy.
审查每份到期的保单是我的工作职责
As a matter of fact，Mr。Abbot was sitting right where you are now
话说那天阿贝特先生就坐在你现在
when we discussed his appeal.
这个位子上和我争论
I…I just don't get it
我…我就是搞不懂
I've been with this insurance company for over ten years.
我给你们公司付了10多年的医保费
I know，Harold，but unfortunately，when we reviewed your claim
我知道，哈罗德，但问题是：在审查过程中
we discovered that you failed to mention a previous condition.
我们发现你没有写明你以前的一项状况
What condition？There's no condition
状况？哪有什么状况？
It says here you had oral surgery to remove a cyst from your jaw.
这份报告上说，你曾动过一次口腔手术，去除了下巴囊肿
This is absurd！I have heart disease
这…简直荒谬！我得的是心脏病！
It has nothing to do with some oral surgery that I had 30 years ago！
和30年前的口腔手术有个鸟关系？！
Any type of oral surgery is going to leave scar tissue.
任何类型的口腔手术都会留下疤痕组织
Scar tissue can lead to gum disease
疤痕会引起牙龈疾病
and as you well know，gum disease can cause heart disease.
而你也该清楚：牙龈疾病会引发心脏病
You know what？You're- You're a criminal
你知道么…你是在杀人！
You are goddamn criminal
你是个挨千刀的杀人犯！
I've paid my monthly premium for ten years without so much as a cold
爷每月付保费花了10年的钱，连感冒都没得过
and now that I'm actually sick，you're gonna deny my coverage？
现在真闹大病了，却只换来一纸否决？
- I have a family！- Those are the rules，Harold！
- 爷要养家糊口！ - 我是按规矩办事，哈罗德
I'm sorry，but your own actions have caused this.
抱歉，这都是你自己造成的代价
You've just given me a death sentence，I mean，who's gonna cover me now？
这代价我怎么担得起？你等于判了我死刑
You just killed me
你这个白眼狼！
I have a family too，so I can empathize with his argument
我也有家人，他发飙我能理解
But basically，the guy lied on his application
但是谁让这家伙当初隐瞒实情呢？
- Whoa，watch it，Will。- What？
- 额…等一下，威廉 - 咋了？
Do you think he did that on purpose？
你是说他是故意的？
All right.
好吧
It wasn't my job to assess what his intentions were
评估他的意图不是我的工作
It was my job to check the accuracy of his claim
我的职责是核对其索赔申请书的准确性
Everybody thinks we're the bad guys.
社会对我们这行总是有偏见，
Nobody mentions the millions of people we help every year
可是，有几个人知道我们每年能帮助数百万人
without inciden.Or the millions of dollars we donate to charity every year
转危为安？有几个人知道我们每年将几百万美金 捐献给慈善机构？
Or all the free clinics we support
又有谁知道我们赞助过多少免费诊所？
- Short answers，Will。Short answers。- Today in probate court，
- 证词要简短，威廉，要有内涵 - “今天在遗嘱检验裁判所，
The assets for one of history's most notorious serial killers
…史上最臭名昭著的连环杀手
John Kramer，were distributed
约翰·克莱默的资产，被依法分配
They were mainly in real estate holdings。But in my time researching…
其中大部分是他生前拥有的房地产集团产权， 不过在本台记者的调查下…
One more question：Who found the error on his application？
弱弱地问一句，是谁发现那申请书里的漏洞的？
The Dog Pen。They work as a team
我手下六人工作组，绰号“疯狗队”
If there's a discrepancy to be found in an application，the six of them will find it.
单据里一出现错误，他们立刻就能搜查出来
Sir，they're waiting for you in the conference room.
威总，他们在会议室等您
Very good.
好的
- How's it going today，people？- Great，
- 今天如何啊，伙计们？ - 很好很强大！
Mr。E.，Found two application errors for a chronically ill client.
盾哥，这位慢性病客户有两处漏洞
This guy practically lives at his doctor's office.
小样儿整天赖在他医生家里
I mean，this could probably save us nearly 200K over his lifetime.
我寻思咱大概可以省下20万
Terminator strikes again.
咱们的终结者又出击了啊
I'll be back in a few hours.
我去开会，几个钟头后回来
Looking good，Hank.
气色不错啊，老汉
Who will offer the most flesh in order to save their life？
为了生命，哪位愿意献出最重的人肉祭品？
The choice is yours.
决定权在于你们
I'm not dying for you，bitch！
我才不会坐以待毙，婊子！
Yeah.
喂？
I'm on my way
我就来
What's going on？
什么情况？
Feds who took over the crime scene are requesting you ASAP.
现场被FBI接管了，他们催你赶紧来
Erickson.
老埃
I didn't know you ever made it out from behind the desk.
没想到你也会来干这种脏活
I make exceptions when fingerprints are found at a Jigsaw murder scene
拼图案现场发现指纹，我就特地过来瞧瞧
Have a look
看这
We also got a right index off the scale.
磅秤那边也有几处相同的
- Been IDed yet？- Yeah。They're Agent Strahm's.
- 验证过没？ - 恩，全部与小斯的指纹吻合
When I learned he and Perez were being targeted by Jigsaw
得知电锯门盯上他和小皮
I should have been more aware，but I didn't see this coming
我本该意识到这点的，可没想到事情会成这样
Not from Peter Strahm
居然是小斯
- It was a shock to all of us。- Yeah.
- 大家都震精了 - 是啊
But we have something he doesn't know about.
不过…有件事他还被蒙在鼓里
Follow me.
跟我来
Lindsey.
琳塞
- Detective Hoffman。- Perez.
- 霍大队长 - 皮瑞兹？！
It was my call，Detective.
这是我的决定，霍警官
I knew that Jigsaw wasn't working alone，
电锯门另有神秘门徒
but until I knew for certain who was helping him
在没查到是谁之前
I couldn't guarantee her well- being
我要确保我部下的安全
- So you let me think she was dead？- Well，I didn't know who I could trust.
- 所以你把全世界人民都耍了？ - 非常时期我选择保密
What else have you been keeping from me？
你们还有多少事瞒着我？
We know that Agent Strahm knew the five people in the real estate scam
我们了解到，先前地产蒙骗案那5个人，小斯都认识
The victims in the traps that Erickson found
就是埃长官找到的那五个受害者
- How did he know？- Strahm and I investigated them after the house fire
- 他怎么会认识？ - 小斯和我曾调查过火灾那案子
It was arson。All five people were accountable
那其实是起纵火案，五人都有责任
But after our lone witness went missing，no charges were ever filed.
但由于我们唯一的证人失踪，最终无法提出对五人的指控
Strahm couldn't let them get away，so he put them in a trap
可能小斯不肯放过他们，所以就设置了
in which slaughtering each other was the only way out.
这场惨烈的五人自相残杀游戏
So what are you telling me？He's a vigilante？
这话是什么意思？他成神雕大侠了么？
Call him whatever you like，but he has to be found.
你怎么称呼都行，总之一定要找到他
We'd like to work together on this.
我们希望能和警方并肩作战
You led me to believe that she was dead，and you want to work with me？
先前忽悠我说她死了，现在又要拉我做事？
Look，we're offering full disclosure，detective
听我说，霍警官，我们已经开诚布公了
So from now on，everything we know，you know.Is that fair？
从现在开始，双方信息同步更新，和谐了吧？
Detective Hoffman。How about a quick word？
霍大队，简单采访您一会儿行吗
Pamela Jenkins，the resident Jigsaw sensation
帕梅拉·詹金斯，“拼图名记”
Just reporting the facts，Detective.
我只是实话实说罢了，霍大队
Is that what you're doing？「John Kramer，conundrum of carnage.」
最近是不是在写那篇？
If you'd like to make a statement on the record
你要是能发表有关的正式声明
I'd be more than happy to take it.
我会更荣幸
You're twisting the facts to make a better story。It's irresponsible
把事实真相曲解成诱人的故事，不负责任
Excuse me。Nice catching up.
又一次见到你很高兴，失陪了
I know more about John Kramer than you might think
关于约翰·克莱默，我手上有你想不到的猛料
Somehow I doubt that
哦？说来听听
Kramer left his wife a box in his will.Did you know that？
克莱默留给他老婆一个盒子作为遗产，这事你知道不？
Maybe I did，maybe I didn't.How do you know it？
也许知道也许不知道，你是怎么知道的？
Probate court。It's public record for those who know where to look.
遗嘱检验法院，这是公开记录，老百姓只要想知道就可以问到
All right。What do you really want？
这样啊，那么你到底想干嘛？
Jill Tuck。Help me get to her and I'll dial down on the sensationalism.
吉儿·塔克.帮个忙，让我找她谈谈，我保证今后不再哗众取宠
Really？I'll see what I can do.
是嘛？这事日后再说
Do you remember how you were transported there？
你还记得被绑架到那里的过程么？
I don't know how I got there.
啥都记不起来了
Just opened my eyes and…He did this to me.
一睁开眼就…是他干的
Who did this？
是谁？
Jigsaw.
拼图杀人狂
- You didn't cut your own arm off？- I did。I did.
- 不是你自己把手砍下来的么？ - 对，是我自己砍自己
But he made me do it.
但都是他逼我的！
Why is that？
他为了什么呢？
Because what Eddie and I were doing was wrong
因为，我和爱迪做了错事
We were…we were ruining people's lives.
我们…我们害死了很多人
He wanted us to learn
他在教训我们
And did you？
那你吸取教训了吗？
Look at me
请你把眼睛睁大点
Look at my goddamn arm！
好好瞧瞧我的胳膊！
What the fuck am I supposed to learn from this？！Huh？
你说我吸取教训了吗？
Look at my arm！What…What am I supposed to learn from this？
看我的胳膊！！说啊！我该吸取什么样的教训！！
- Just breathe。- Look at me！
- 请你冷静 - 你回来！
Hello Gillian！
你好啊？丁丁宝宝
- It's a good name，hon。- Wow，Wow.
- 这名字真好听，老公 - 哇哦，哇哦
Could have been Scarlet.But，no，has to be a boy.
本来想取「斯嘉丽」.但是咱家宝宝是男孩嘛
Let me see if I can get all three of us in there.
让爸爸看看镜头装不装得下咱一家人
Snuggle around here.Lean inside。There we go.
来，抱紧，靠近点，笑一笑
- There we are。- Hey，Gideon.
- 拍个合家欢 - 嘿，吉丁
Here's a little happy family.
幸福的一家啊
- We love you，Son。We're waiting for you。- We love you.
- 爸爸妈妈爱你，儿子，在等你出来哦 - 我们爱你
If you're watching this，Jill，I'm long gone from this world.
当你看这盘录像带的时候，吉儿，我已经不在人世了
I'm leaving you a box today，and its contents are of grave importance.
我今天留了个宝盒给你，里面的东西至关重要
Hello。I'm not in right now，but please leave a message.
你好，我现在不在家，有事请留言
Miss Tuck，this is Pamela Jenkins calling，yet again.
塔克女士，你好，又是我，帕梅拉·詹金斯
I was hoping you can clear some things up for me about your husband.
我想问您一些有关您前夫的事
Let me buy you lunch or a cup of coffee.
能否赏脸一起吃顿午饭或者咖啡什么的
I've found something interesting about John Kramer's death.
关于约翰·克莱默，我发现了一些有趣的东西
Are you there，Detective？
是你吗？警官
By hearing this tape，some will likely assume this Is over.
听到这盘带子，有人一定以为一切都结束了
You feel you now have control，don't you？
你觉得可以掌控局势了是吗？
You think you will walk away untested.
你以为不经过考验就太平了？
Look here.
看这
These are the Jigsaw pieces carved from previous victims
这张是以前那些死者身上的拼图
This is the piece taken from the latest victim
而那张是最近一次的
- It looks like all the rest - Yeah，that's what we said，too.
- 不是一样的么？ - 是啊，一开始我们也这么认为
The skin abrasions，they're indicative of a knife of a partially serrated edge.
对比拼图印记，最近这次的是用一种锯齿缘刀切割而成
- So？- So，all of the other cuts were made
- 那以前的呢？ - 以前的则是由某种近乎完美的
with a near- perfect blade of surgical quality.
高质量手术刀切出来的
Obviously，Strahm used a different knife than John Kramer.
看来斯特拉姆用的刀不一样
Right，but it got us curious，so we pulled the files to compare
恩，不过这线索引起了我们的注意，我们对所有拼图印记做两相比较
That same knife was used on only one other victim
发现只有一名死者身上的拼图与其纹路一致
That victim was Seth Baxter
是塞斯·巴克斯特
The man who killed your sister.
那个杀你妹妹的人
You're telling me that you can tell a different knife was used from a photo？
你们光凭照片就能看出割印记用的刀不一样？
No，but I can.I was the one who examined that body.
他们不能，但我能.塞斯的尸体，是我解剖的
I've examined every body of the Jigsaw Killer.
实际上所有拼图案的尸体，都是我解剖的
Good work.
解剖帝
The tape from the latest victim was missing，so we're looking into the Seth Baxter tape.
在割肉游戏现场没有找到录像带，所以我们在找塞斯的那盘带子
- Why's that？- Well，if a different person cut the piece，
- 找来组撒？ - 我在想，既然拼图印记有可能是山寨的
then maybe a different person made the tape，too.
那么录像带也有可能是盗版的
- Strahm？- Yeah，maybe.
- 是斯特拉姆？ - 是啊，有可能
Strahm's voice on the tape would be our smoking gun.
如果查出录像里是小斯的声音那就证据确凿了
We have that，we could go public with his involvement.
就可以正式颁布全国通缉令
Hey，Jill.
嘿，吉儿
- But that's not what the prescription… - I'm sick！
- 可那不是我们所开的方… - 我得病了！
- Look at me！Look at me！- Jane，Jane，it's ok，allright？Relax
- 看着我！看着我！- 简，简，没事的，好吗？淡定
I didn't expect to see you here so soon.
这么急着见我？
Change of plans.
计划不如变化
- The game begins tonight。- Why？
- 游戏今晚开始 - 咋的？
Because somebody knows about the box that shouldn't.
因为有人知道了宝箱的事
- Who？- That's not your concern.
- 谁？ - 这个你甭管
All you need to know is that：from now on，I control all aspects of the game.
你只要明白一点：从现在开始，这场游戏我做主
That's not what John wanted.
约翰可不是这么想的
Give me the envelopes。That's not a request.
把信封交出来，我这可不是在求你
Here.
给
From now on，I work alone.
从今儿起，我单飞
I know.I'm only carrying out John's final request.
我懂.我只是在了结约翰最后的遗愿
Well，John's dead。And his work is almost done
老头已经死了，电锯门完蛋了
- Who's this？- Unfinished business.
- 介寺谁？- 未竟的任务
When I'm done，we no longer speak.
事成之后，你我各安天命
- …forty-five minutes。- Yes，I understand that.
- 45分钟 - 是，我知道
- Please！Please。- But we have to wait for the doctor.
- 求你了！求求你！- 我们得等医生
Let my hand go.
你松开！
Methadone is only a masking agent。It doesn't heal; it just simply numbs the senses
美沙酮（戒毒用品，类似吗啡）只是个幌子，它治标不治本
I've found a better way
我找到了一种更有效的救人方式
These people，they will continue to hurt you，and let you down.
这些人，他们还会继续伤害你令你失望
They're addicts，John。Recovery is a process.
他们是吸毒者，约翰，戒毒需要过程
Maybe addiction is just a part of human nature.
也许依赖是人的一种本性
But what about these people，Jill，who come here every day
可是这些人，吉儿，这些每天在这进进出出的人
and use you？They bide their time.They're avoiding prison sentences
他们在利用你，戒的不是毒，是寂寞.逃避牢狱之灾
They're getting hooked on masking agents，Do you call that recovery？
吸食吗啡成瘾，你管这叫“戒毒”？
It's not that simple.
戒毒不是那么简单的
Addiction is not simple，Jill！Wake up！
做伸手党却很简单，吉儿！醒醒吧！
These people have no respect for the lives that they're destroying
这些自毁人生的人对生命没有丝毫的尊重
Once you see death up close，
人只有到生死攸关的时刻，
then you know what the value of life is
才真正懂得人生价值
And that's my way.
这就是我的方式
And I brought proof that it works.
我把能证明其有效的证据带来了
- Amanda？- Hello，Jill.
- 阿曼达？ - 好啊，吉儿
Jill，
吉儿
you once told me that she was a lost soul.
你曾跟我说，她迷失了灵魂
But here she stands.
现在，她就在这
She's clean and whole.
她接受了洗礼，脱胎换骨
And she has a new appreciation for her life.
不再浑噩，对重生满怀感激
It works。It's real。He helped me.
没错，确实行之有效，门主救了我
It's not alarmism and mystify
并不是危言耸听，装神弄鬼
But there are signs that trouble is back
但种种迹象告诉我们麻烦事又来了
Even though the police believe that John Kramer AKA（as known as） Jigsaw is died
尽管警方已确认拼图杀人狂约翰克莱默已死亡
But this passed week a new sort cold game was discovered with grossly result
然而就在上周，可怕的事实表明：拼图杀人游戏再度发生了
Victims included anyone associate with
凶犯杀人的手法
the life of John Kramer however remote
与拼图杀人狂极为相似
The jigsaw killer maybe dead，but the murders continued
拼图杀人狂已死，但虐杀却仍在继续
Shit！
妈的！
Hank，you still here？
汉克，你还在不？
Don't fucking move.
不许动！
Shit！Oh，fuck！Okay.
我…日！我操！没事的
Okay，I'm gonna take care of you。Just… Where'd you get hit？You wearing a vest？
我会救你的，别怕，内家伙在哪？你怎么穿着马甲啊？
Hello，William.
你好啊，威廉
Oh，Jesus.
我地妈…
You've probably been wondering when we would see each other again.
你可能想过你我何时会再次见面
- Today is that day。- No！
- 就在今天 - 不！！
For years，your probability formula has decided the fate of others.
多年来，你的概率公式理论左右了不少人的命运
The healthy have benefited
健康的人受益
while the potentially sick have been unjustly rejected.
而生病的人却被不公平地拒绝接受保险
However，this formula does not take into account the human will to live.
但是你的理论没有考虑到人的求生欲望
When faced with death，
面对死亡
who should live versus who will live are two entirely separate things.
“应该活命者”和“能够生存者”是两个截然不同的概念
Today，your policy will be put to the test.
今天你的理论将要受到考验
There are four straps around your limbs，and you have four tests you must complete，
你的四肢都被安装了引爆装置，你必须完成四个游戏任务
for if you don't，the straps on your arms and legs will detonate.
但如果你拒绝参与游戏，便四处爆炸
Look closely.
仔细看
Oh，shit！
我操！
You have 60 minutes to complete your tests and avoid this fate，starting now.
60分钟内必须完成全部任务，否则下场如此， 现在开始计时
You are not alone in this game.
这一路你并不孤单
Just as you have taken loved ones away from their families，
如同你害死别人的亲人那样
if you don't reach the end before the timer hits zero
一旦你时间用尽而又没能通关，
you will never see your family again.
就再也见不到你的家人
Mom？Mom！Mom。Mom，wake up！Mom.
妈妈？妈妈！醒醒，妈妈！
Mom.
妈妈
- Where are we？- I don't know.
- 我们介寺在哪？ - 母鸡
- What's that？- I don't know
- 那是什么？ - 不知道啊
Oh，my God.
额的个神呐…
Here is your first test.
这是你的第一个考验
Your health and military background puts you in the highest category of success.
你健康的体魄和军人出身为你取得了巨大成功
However，the same cannot be said for your adversary.
面前这个对手跟你大相径庭
At only 52 years of age，this man has continued to smoke
52年来，即便身患高血压和心脏病，
even though he has a history of high blood pressure and heart disease.
这个人仍然吸烟过度
This demonstrates his appreciation of the blessings of his own life
看来他对自己的幸福人生很是满意
Your game will focus on a simple element.
你的这款游戏纠结于一种简单的元素：氧气
From there，once this game begins，every time you take a breath，
游戏启动后，你每吸一口氧气
the clamps around your chest will close in and crush your body.
腰部巨钳都会夹紧，直到挤碎你的身体
The only way to escape is in the other's failure.
唯一的胜利条件就是对方的失败
So I ask you，when faced with death，who will survive？
所以我想问你的是：面对死亡威胁，谁能生存下来？
Live or die，William。Make your choice.
是生是死，威廉，做出你的决定
- Fuck you！！- Who the hell is that？！
- 决你妈！！ - 那扇贝到底是谁！！
Hold your breath
屏住呼吸！
What the fuck？Oh，Jesus！
我操！耶稣啊！
Come on！Come on！
快啊！快点啊！
Shit！
靠！
（腐蚀性物品）
Please help us！
请救救我们！
Help us！Someone，please！Please！Help us！
救我们啊！救命啊！救人呐！求求你们！
Somebody，please！Please！Please，somebody help！
来人救命啊！救命啊！有没有人？求你了！
Anybody？
来人呐！
「Live」。「Die」。What the fuck？
“生”？“死”？这什么玩意儿？
It's connected to that.
连着内个
- 「H- F」。What does that stand for？- Hydrofluoric acid.
- “H- F”？ 那是什么 - 是“万腐之王”氢氟酸
This stuff will eat through human flesh within seconds.
人身上一沾这鬼东西，瞬间就被腐蚀掉
- What should we do？- Pull the lever。You want to live，don't you？
- 我们怎么办 - 拉这个扳手吧，咱要求“生”存，对吧？
What about the timer？It has to mean something
那计时器又是什么？算什么意思？
I don't know，I don't even know why we're here
我不知道，我都不知道为什么我们会在这！
We're here because your father
我们在这，是因为你爸爸
Miss Jenkins.
詹金斯小姐
Please，this will only take a second.We can help each other.
求你了，很快就好，我们可以互利互助
What makes you think you can come to my door like this？
是什么让你觉得我俩可以互利互助？
Because I found something you'll want to see
我找到了一样你一定很想看到的东西
Go on.
看吧
- Where'd you get this？- It was at the location where John died.
- 你在哪找到的？ - 就在约翰死的那个肉厂
- Does it mean anything to you？- No.
- 怎么样，有帮助吧？ - 没有
Goodbye，Miss Jenkins.
再见了，詹小姐
If you think of anything.
想到什么就打给我
（那次派对）
I want to thank you for sponsoring this party，William.
非常感谢你对这次派对的鼎力支持，威廉
and I know how much the clinic appreciates it.
诊所的开办也要好好谢谢你们公司的赞助
- John Kramer。- William Easton.
- 约翰·克莱默 - 威廉·伊斯盾
- Kramer？You're Jill's husband，right？- I am.
- 克莱默？哦您是吉女士的丈夫吧？ - 是的
- Nice to meet you。- Nice to meet you.
- 很高兴见到你 - 我也是
Sounds like we're in a similar business，John.
貌似你们和我们算是同道中人呢，老翰
Oh，yeah？How's that？
哦是吗？怎么说？
Well，you try to predict people's behavior。So do I
你们诊所试图预测病人的行为，我们也是
People count on us for coverage，
人们找上我们是求一个依靠
and we have to analyze each person for the probability of success.
我们得仔细分析每个客户的可服务性
- How do you do that？- Well，it's a formula.
- 你们是怎么分析的？ - 我们有一套公式
It's pretty complicated，actually，
说起来有点复杂，不过大体上
but，in essence，it breaks down to monthly payments
是这样算的：“按月支付能力”
multiplied by lifespan minus the probability of illness.
乘以“预期生命期限” 减去“患病概率”
and if its sum is positive，we consider coverage.
得出结果是正数的话就可以考虑为其办理医保
- Who devised that formula？- Me.
- 这公式是谁发明的？ - 本盾
So，in a sense… you choose who lives or dies？
如此说来，在某种程度上，你能选择谁生谁死？
No，I，uh… No，I'd say I decide which people have the potential
啊不是，我是说我选择那些更有潜力活下去的人
to live long，healthy lives.
那些健康长寿的人
But you're not taking into onsideration the most important human element of all.
但你无视了生存法则中最重要的一个人为因素
- Which is what？- The will to live.
- 是什么？ - 求生意志
Until a person is faced with death，
只有当一个人面对生死关头，
it's impossible to tell whether the have what it takes to survive.
才能判断出他是否有继续生存下去的可能性
（抓住两头）
Fuck that.
抓你妹
Shit.
日！
Hello，William.
你好，威廉
Standing on the platforms behind me are two of your colleagues.
站在我背后平台上的，是你的两个部下
One，your file clerk。a young，healthy male with no living relatives.
一个，是文档管理员阿伦：一个无亲无故的健康小伙子
The other，a middle- aged woman with a family history of diabetes.
另一个，是中年女接线员阿蒂嫂，她有家族糖尿病史
According to your policy，your secretary is older and weaker and
根据你的理论，年迈体弱的阿蒂嫂
and therefore less worthy to survive.
不值得活下去
But you know the loss that she will be to her family
但你也该知道她的死亡会对其家人造成多大的打击
while young Allen will disappear without a blip on the world's radar.
而若选择救阿蒂嫂，那么阿伦将人间蒸发，消失得无影无踪
Only one can exit this room，and the choice of whom falls upon you.
只有一个人可以出这屋，选择权在你手上
You must let go of the one to save the life of the other.
想要救其中一个，就必须牺牲另一个
As you can see，the choice is not so clear
就像你所看到的，这种情况远比你面对
when you are face to face with the people whose blood will stain your hands.
那些血会弄污你的手的投保者棘手得多
Let the game begin.
游戏开始
Wait！No！No，wait！I won't do this！I won't do this！
等等！别走！等下！不！我不会那么做的！我不会那么做的！
William！
威总！
It's a business！My decisions aren't made this way！
介揍寺僧活！那不是我的本意！
No！I'm not going to do it！I'm not going to do it！
我不会放手的！我不放手！！
I'm not going to do it！
我绝不松手！
- Stop it！！- Please…help me…
- 停下来！！ - 救救我…求你！
- I'm sorry。- No！No！
- 对不起 - 不！不！
I'm sorry.
对不起…
Thank you。Thank you！
呜呜…谢谢…谢谢
You try to find a way out of here，Addy。I have to keep going。Be careful.
阿蒂嫂，想办法逃出去吧，我还得赶路，你自己小心点
What if we put acid on the metal bars？It'll eat through the metal，won't it？
把这酸液泼铁栏杆会怎样？能腐蚀掉铁栏杆，对吧？
Yeah，but how are we going to get it on the bars？With our hands？
能，可是我们怎么泼？用手盛吗？
What are you looking at？
你在看什么？
I wonder… The mirror.
我想知道…这镜子后面
- What？- Who's behind the glass？
- 怎么了？ - 是谁在镜子后面监视我们
What do you want！
你要干什么！
Why are you doing this？
为什么要这么做！！
Somebody help me，please.Please help me.
来人救命啊！求你了！请救救我！！
Hello，Pamela.You've sensationalized my life，
你好，帕梅拉，你为了自身利益曲解真相
twisting the truth and exploiting my message for your own benefit.
耸人听闻，恶意诋毁我的生活…
- Hoffman。- It's Erickson.
- 我是 - 是我，埃里克森
- We found the Seth Baxter tape。- Yeah？
- 我们找到了塞斯·巴克斯特的带子 - 是嘛？
But there was something else we wanted to discuss with you.
有件事想跟你讨论
- What's that？- Better to talk about it in person.
- 什么事？ - 还是当面谈比较好
It's time- sensitive.
赶紧过来吧
I'll be right there.
我很快就来
Excuse me.
请问一下
- Just down there。- Thank you.
- 往前走几步就到 - 唔该
The device Timothy is strapped to is my personal favorite。I call it The Rack.
这套捆绑蒂莫西的机器是我的大爱，我取名为“人体扭转机”
Last- minute tweaks？Told you he'd fuck with it.
临时抱佛脚？我早说过他搞不好
If you switch the gear ratio，
如果你要切换齿轮转速
you have to change the gear grease to match the increased friction.
就得更改齿轮油以降低摩擦力
Maybe you should stick to the heavy lifting.
我看给你配台起重机算了
You need five- weight.
小样儿该减肥了
It's in the gun.
枪的机关可别再弄错了
Check with me next time.
下次想修改要先通知我
How many next times are there gonna be？
我们还有几个“下次”？
However many there needs to be.
世间需要几次，我们就玩几次
That's a human being.
那毕竟是个活生生的人
Do you like how brutality feels，Mark？
你就那么崇尚暴力吗？马克
Let's be honest。You want him to suffer just as much as I do.
咱们打开天窗说亮话吧，你我都是施虐狂
- So when's your test，detective？- I don't need one.
- 什么时候轮到你玩游戏啊？警官 - 我不需要玩
- Oh，yeah？- Yeah.
- 哦？是吗？ - 是啊
Because I don't take life for granted.
因为，我不会像某人那样不把生命当回事
You're still dragging your knuckles on the ground.
这方面你还处于菜鸟级别
What do you know about life？
你对生命了解多少？
Get used to me，'cause I'm not going anywhere.
你得习惯我唠叨，因为我会一直在这陪门主
You sure about that？
认真你就输了
Time is short.
时候不早了
You okay？
您还好吗？
Now it's time to get Dr。Denlon from the hospital.
你该去医院把戴伦医生带来了
Okay。I'll take you back.
谨遵师旨，这就去办
Go。Be quick.
快去快回
- Why'd you come here？- John，stop
- 你来干什么？ - 约翰，停手吧
- Don't do this。- I promise you
- 别再干了 - 我向你保证
when all this is done
等一切都结束
I will provide a way out for you.
我保你全身而退
I wish that time was now.
我真希望是现在
I have something for you.
我有东西要给你
What is it for？
这是干吗？
When the time's right，you'll know what to do with it.
时辰一到，你便知晓
Shit！
操
（最终决定）
I came to talk to you，Will，because
我得跟你谈谈，威廉，是这么回事
I've found a treatment for my cancer that I think holds a lot of promise，
我找到一套很有可能治好我癌症的疗法
but my requests for coverage
但是我申请的医保理赔
have all been turned down.
却全部遭拒绝
So I was hoping that maybe if I came and explained it to you，
所以我想当面来跟你解释一下
that you might be able to get that overturned for me.
你看能不能帮我这个忙
- Well，the buck stops here，John。Fire away。- Okay.
- 我职责所在，你说吧，老翰 - 好
This is a doctor in Norway
这是位挪威医生
He's got a thirty to forty percent success rate with gene therapy.
他的基因治疗技术成功率达到了30- 40%
He injects what he calls suicide genes into cancerous tumor cells
他把名为“自杀式细胞”的基因注入癌变肿瘤细胞中
then any inactive form of a toxic drug is administered and it…
能使细胞对抗癌药物更敏感，然后就可以…
Yes，I'm familiar with the therapy you're talking about.
恩，我听说过这种“基因治癌”
Right。And a new trial's starting.
没错，这位医生正开展一项新试验
He's looking for new patients，
他在找新的试验对象
and he seems to think that I'm the perfect candidate.
他觉得我是最佳人选
John，if your primary physician，Dr。Gordon，thought you were a suitable candidate，
老翰，要是你的主治医师哥登医生觉得你是最佳人选的话
- he would have pursued it。- No.
- 他早就治好你了 - 切！
Dr。Gordon is a specialist。You know，he's making money on his speciality.
哥登医生确实是个专家，但他专的不是脑瘤而是钱
He's not a thinker.
他是个自我主义者
I mean，the man has his hand on the doorknob half the time that I'm there.
站在我病床边没一会工夫就开门走了
I'm gonna be straight with you。At your age and with the development of your cancer，
约翰，别怪我说话直，像你这么大岁数得癌症
it's simply not feasible for Umbrella Health…
想治愈恐怕没有可行性…
Wait，wait，wait，wait。What's not feasible？
你等会，等会，什么叫做可行性？
By whose mathematical equation is this not feasible？
你通过哪位数学大师的计算方法得出这事没有可行性？
It's policy，John。It's policy.
这是国家政策，老翰，是政策
And if you go outside the system to seek out this treatment，
你跳出体制去做那种公认的无效治疗
which has been deemed ineffective，you will be in breach of policy
就肯定会因为违反政策
and you will be dropped from coverage completely.
而被拒绝理赔
I'm sorry.
很抱歉
Did you know that in the Far East，
你知道吗，在东方的天朝
people pay their doctors when they're healthy？
人们身体健康的时候要付医生钱
When they're sick，they don't have to pay.
而得病则不用支付
So，basically，they end up paying for what they want，
所以基本上那儿的人
not what they don't want.
是“按需付费”
We got it all ass- backwards here.
但我们美国却正好相反
These politicians，they say the same thing，over and over and over again.
这些所谓的政客，每天说着千篇一律的空话
「Healthcare decisions should be made by doctors and their patients，
说什么“医疗对策应由医生和病人来判定
「not by the government.」
而不是由政府来决定”
Well，now I know they're not made by doctors and their patients
得，现在我才知道
or by the government.
原来都不是由这三者决定
They're made by the fucking insurance companies.
而是他妈的保险公司
Piranha.
食人鱼
John，please.If you do this，you'll be on your own，
老翰，听我说，如果你非要这么做，于你自己不利
and the subsequent cost to you will be staggering.
而且随之而来的花销将是惊人的天文数字
Don't talk to me about money。I have money.
别跟我提钱，我不差钱
This is about principle.
这是原则问题
You see，Will… this is my life we're talkin' about.
威廉，我们谈的是我的生命
- You remember？- What about Jill's life？
- 你忘了吗？ - 那么吉儿呢？
How's she going to be taken care of when you're gone？
你去挪威谁来照顾她？
You let me worry about Jill.
这事用不着你为我操心
The type of cancer you have is malignant and inoperable.
你得的癌症既致命又不能用手术治疗
That rolled off your tongue real smooth.
这话从你嘴里不知道说几遍了
Even if the treatment works，the cancer will return eventually.
就算治疗起效果了，最终癌魔还是会回归
- It's an unwinnable battle。- That was even smoother.
- 这是一场永远也打不赢的仗！ - 这次的借口更圆滑了
As a matter of fact，that was downright slick.
实际上就是这是一种最最陈腐的思想！
You think it's the living that will have ultimate judgement over you，
你以为只有活人才能对你终审
because the dead will have no claim over your soul.
而死人是不会有怨言的是吗？
but you may be mistaken.
侬搞错特乐！
Oh，shit！
我操！
Hello，William.You have seen the flaws in your policy.
你好，威廉，已经认识到你理论中的错误了吧
But what you have not seen is the extent some people will go to
但是你还没见过面对生死关头
when faced with death.
有一种人会达到的境界
The lawyer from your firm has…
你单位里的那位律师
- Debbie！- …90seconds to cross this room
- 黛比！ - 必须在90秒时间内穿越这间游戏室
or the device attached to her chest will discharge and pierce her brain.
否则，安装在她胸前的机关启动后将射爆她的脑袋
It's gonna be okay。You're gonna be okay.
别怕，没事的！会没事的！
She will find that the journey across this room is filled with danger.
穿越过程中她会遇到重重危险
In order for her to make it，you will need to be there for her，
为了帮助她通过此关，你也必须到达指定地点
and it is you who ultimately holds the key to her survival.
因为你就是决定其能否生存下去的最大因素
When faced with death，will she have the skills to live？
面对死亡，她拥有原地复活的技能吗？
Let the game begin.
游戏开始
Okay。Okay，listen！
好吧，黛比，淡定啊！
- Jesus Christ！What the fuck is this？- Debbie！Debbie！Listen to me！
- 你娘里个脚！这什么玩意儿！ - 黛比！黛比！听我说！
- Debbie！Okay，Debbie，listen to me！Debbie！- What is this？
- 黛比！没事的，听我说！黛比！ - 这什么啊？！
- Get me the fuck out of here！- Get through the maze
- 快放老娘出去！ - 尽快穿越这个迷宫
as fast as you can。Listen to me！
听我说，尽快穿过去！
- Get me out of here！- Debbie！
- 快放我出去！！ - 黛比！
Okay。You've got to get through this maze as fast as you can！Go！Move now！Go now！
你要以最快速度穿过这个迷宫！听见没！快去吧！快啊！
Come on！You can make it！You can make it！You got to keep moving！Go！
加油！你能行的！你能行的！一直往前走！上吧！
- Will，this is insane！I can't！- Go！You can make it！
- 威廉！这太疯狂了！我不敢！ - 加油！你一定可以的！
Come on！You can make it！You've got to keep moving！
加油啊！你可以的！动起来！别停下来！
（替她解围）
Wait a minute！I think I can help you up here！
坚持一会！我来帮你！
Maybe this will stop it！
可能这样可以停下来！
Yes！Yes！
好的！好的！
Do it again！It worked！It worked！
再来啊！有效果了！这招有用！
- Do it again！It worked，it worked，it worked！- Okay！Ready？
- 再来！这个有用！这个好！ - 好！准备好没！
- Yes！- Go！
- 好了！ - 走！
Keep moving！Don't stop！Keep going！Keep going！Keep going！
继续冲，别停下！继续冲！继续冲！继续冲！
Don't stop！
别歇着！
You gotta keep going！Keep going！Go！Go！
继续冲啊！继续往前！冲啊！冲！
Keep moving！Go！Go！Go！
继续冲！冲冲冲！
Fuck，I can't！It's a fucking trap！There's no way out！
冲你娘里个脚啊！妈的是个陷阱！我过不去！
It's a fucking trap！I can't！
妈的！这是个陷阱！我过不去！
No！No，there's a ladder at the end！So just go under！I'll help you！
不，不！前面有个梯子！走到那下边！我帮你！
Ready？
准备好没？
Go！
冲！
God！Come on，Debbie，go！Climb！Climb！
上帝啊！加油啊，黛比，上啊！爬上来！爬上来！
Come on！Come on，you're almost there！You're almost there！
加油！加油！就快到了！就快到了！
Go！Go！Go！
快！快！快！
Okay，look for a key.There's got to be a key！Look for a key！
好了，快找钥匙！这里应该有把钥匙！找钥匙！
What？
什么？
What are you waiting for？
你还在等什么！
- It's in you。- What？
- 是你！ - 纳尼？！
- It's fucking inside you！- Oh，fuck！
- 狗日的在你肚子里！ - 我操！
Okay。Okay，I can do this。Wait！
好吧，好吧，我来取，你干吗！
- What the fuck are you doing？- I need that fucking key！
- 你这臭娘们儿作死啊！ - 老娘要的是钥匙！
I can get it！I can get it！I can get it！
我会取的！我会取出来的！我会取出来的！
God！No！God！No！
天那！不！！天那！
Hello，Pamela.
你好，帕梅拉
Well，today you will experience the meaning of sacrifice.
今天，你将体会到“牺牲”的意义
And you will see the consequence for those who unjustly hurt others.
目睹那些害人虫的下场
Fuck！
妈的！
（启动它）
Someone's there。They're watching us.
肯定有人在那边在监视咱们
Why？Why would someone do this？
为什么？这是为什么呢？
To see how we respond.
想看我们的反应
They want to know what decision we'll make.
他们想知道我们会做什么决定
- Let's pull it。- No！We don't know what it does yet.
- 我们推手闸吧 - 不行！我们还不知道会发生什么！
It's too risky.
太冒险了
Fuck！
操！
Hey.
嘿
- Thanks for coming in。- What'd you find？
- 来了啊，辛苦 - 发现什么线索？
- An abnormality in Strahm's fingerprint。- What？
- 关于小斯指纹的一个疑点 - 是什么？
Take a look.
去看看吧
See，the human fingerprint leaves an oily residue
人体的指纹会留有污渍
Depending on how long it's been exposed to the elements
沾有何种残渣，取决于在何种
- it's highly susceptible to contamination。- So what's the problem？
- 外部环境中，暴露了多长时间 - 那么有什么问题吗？
Well，we found trace amounts of Halomethane R- 12.
我们在小斯的指纹中发现了“制冷剂R- 12”
She means Freon
就是“氟利昂”
Production of R- 12 ceased in 1994，
1994年以来国家规定停止使用制冷剂R- 12，
So the question is，was the contaminant we found at the site already
所以问题是： 氟利昂是案发现场原本就存在的呢
or did Strahm bring it in with him？
还是小斯带过去的
We're looking into the building's function
我们在深入调查那幢房子
before it was abandoned.
废弃之前的情况
Excuse me.
接个电话
Did anything come off of the Seth Baxter tape？
塞斯·巴克斯特的录像带有没查出来什么？
Uh，yeah，actually。We might be on to something.
哦，对，我估摸着快好了吧
The tape was in pretty rough shape when we found it，
塞斯的那盘带子很旧了
but we were able to authenticate it.
不过还是可以进行分析
The voice was intentionally distorted，but it didn't match John Kramer's.
带中声音被刻意做得很混沌，但已确定和老头的声音不匹配
- It's currently being analyzed。- For what？
- 技术组正在进行识别 - 识别什么？
Well，we're trying to descramble the tape to find the original voice.
声纹识别，将变声还原成原声
He's on with the tech right now.
老埃正在跟技术组的人联系
You timing something？Your watch.
你约了其他事么？你的表…
Oh，I was before I got your call.
哦，没有，来这之前的事了
We got it。This is our smoking gun.
有信儿了！这下证据确凿了！
The lab's off- site。Come on.
技术组说结果快出来了，走吧
- You're coming，right？- Of course.
- 你也一块去对吧？ - 当然
You shut up！All you do is try to take over every situation.
你可拉倒吧！你每次就知道充大头！
You don't know what the fuck you're talking about！
瞎吵吵什么玩意儿！
Shut the fuck up！
你他妈再说一个？
- Fuck off！- Would you two just shut up already！
- 滚犊子！ - 你们俩都把嘴给我闭上行不！
We can figure this out.
慢慢想办法
- Hey！Who's in there？- Mr。Easton？Is that you？
- 嘿！谁在里面！ - 盾哥？是你吗盾哥？
- Yeah，Shelby？Who's in there with you？- Mr。Easton！
- 是我，是西尔比吗？你和谁在一起？ - 盾哥！
We are all here，sir，all 6。What the hell is going on？
我们6个都在这，哥，这是怎么一回事？？
Everybody！We need your help.
大家都在，我们需要你的帮助！
What can you see？
你们看见什么了？
We can't see anything。It's pitch dark.
啥也没见着啊，这儿黑忽忽的
- What's that sound？- I don't know，something we're chained to.
- 内是什么声音？ - 不道啊，好像是金属的声音
- It's spinning。Oh，God。- Get us out of here！
- 为什么我们在转悠？ - 快放我们出去！
- You have to help us！- Please！
- 快来救我们！ - 求你了！
Come on，get us out of here，Mr。E！
快啊！盾哥！救我们出去！
Mr。Easton！
盾哥！
Mr。Easton！You got to get us out of here！
盾哥！你要救我们出去的啊！
Oh，my God！
我地妈！
Mr。Easton！Mr。Easton！
盾哥！盾哥！
Please！Please get us out of here！Please！
求您救我们出去！求求你了！
Mr。Easton，what is this？
盾哥，这到底怎么回事？！
It's a game.
这是场游戏
game？
游戏？什么鸡吧游戏？！
Hello，William。Before you are six of your most valuable associates，
你好，威廉，面前这六位是你最得力的干将
the ones who find errors in policies.
“找漏洞六人小组”
Their findings result in over two- thirds
他们钻的空子导致三分之二的索赔申请
of all applications denied or prematurely terminated.
或最终驳回，或过早中止
Now you must apply your analysis to them。And will you be able to find their errors？
现在轮到你对他们进行分析了，找出他们这些人的“漏洞”
Six ride the carousel.
六人骑木马
But only two can get off.
只许二人下
The decision of which two survive falls upon you.
究竟选哪个？由你来选择
But remember.the mounted gun will continue to fire
规则第一项
until all six rounds are spent.
六轮开六枪
And if no decision is made on your part，all six will perish.
行动须趁早，团灭不得鸟
What？What？
啥？啥玩意儿？
To offer the two reprieves，
救人先推手
you must press both buttons at once in the box before you.
盒中按电钮
However，in doing so you'll give a sacrifice of your own.
若为自由故，两手皆抽搐
Two can live，four will die.
二人生，四人死
Your decision's symbolized by the blood on your hands.
鲜血即标尺
Wake up！You've got to get us out of here！
盾哥！别愣着啊！侬要救阿拉册七的呀！
Listen to me！I am the one who should live.
救我吧！我是该下马的那一个！
Fuck！
卧槽…
Jesus Christ！
草泥马！！
Please！Mr。Easton！Mr。Easton！Please！
求求你！盾哥！求求你！盾哥！
Please！Follow policy，Mr。Easton！Follow the policy！Please！
求你了！盾爷！救我啊！！快按那按钮！！救我！
- No！- Oh，my God！
- 不！ - 我的天那！
What the fuck！
什么玩意你说！
You always said we're only as strong as the weakest link！
盾哥！你不是经常说“百密必有一洞”么！
I'm the strongest！You can't let me die！
我找的漏洞最多！不能让我死！
Fuck him！I'm healthy，sir。I'm healthy！Please！
死去！我最健康！我身体倍儿棒！
Mr。Easton，come on！
盾哥！快啊！
No，I have two kids.You know them well.
我有两个孩子！您见过的！
Please，they can't get on without me！They need me！
我要是死了，他们怎么办！孩子们需要我！！
Oh，shit！
我日！
Thank you！Thank you！
谢谢…谢谢
- Fucking hell！- Thank you.
- 操你个蛋！ - 谢谢！
Why her？！You don't even know her！Mr。Easton！
干嘛选她！你根本不了解她！盾哥！
Listen to me，okay？My parents are sick，okay？
听我说好么？我父母都有病…
- They need me。I'm all they have，please！- You fucking liar！
- 他们要靠我照顾，他们只能靠我了！ - 别搁那装人了！
- Your parents hate you！They cut you off！- What？
- 你爹妈恨你！早和你断绝关系了！ - 纳尼？！
- Shut up！That's not true！- Fuck you，it is true。I sit next to you！
- 拉倒吧！装什么玩意儿装！ - 装你妈逼，是真的！你这人怎么这样！
- I… I'm pregnant。I'm pregnant！- No，she's not！She's lying！
- 我…我怀孕了，我怀孕了！ - 扯你个鸟淡！她在扯淡！
- She's fucking lying！- Fuck you！
- 她是个大忽悠！盾爷，别信她鬼扯！ - 操你！
- Mr。Easton，she is lying！- I'm pregnant！
- 盾哥，她在骗你！ - 我真的怀孕了！
- She's lying。- No！No，fuck！
- 她撒谎！ - 没有！妈的，真没有！
Please！Please！Push the thing！
快点，快点，求你了！
Push it！
快按啊！
Oh，God！What the…
靠！
What the fuck！
他妈个B！
Mr。Easton！My parents are loaded！
盾哥！我家里钱多多！
They'll give you whatever you want！
只要你救我，想要多少都给你！
- Just say a number！- He's a thief！
- 你说个数！ - 他是个小偷！
He's been stealing from the company for years！
这些年不知道偷了公司多少钱！
It's true！It's true！It's true！
是真的！是真的！是真的！
- Thief！- Fuck you！
- 小偷！ - 草泥马！
Don't listen to them！
别信他们！
- Don't listen to them，Mr。E！- It's true！
- 别听他们的，盾哥！ - 是真的！
Christ！Mr。Easton，come on！Mr。Easton…
上帝啊，盾哥！快按啊！盾哥！
Okay，Mr。Easton，listen to me carefully。I'm on your side，and I can help you.
盾爷，听我说！我对你一片忠心！我来帮你选哪个！
- But you cannot trust this bitch！- What？Fuck you！
- 不要相信这个婊子！ - 嘛玩意儿？！
You cannot believe her.She has already tried to lie！
她在骗你！别信她！
And she's just going to continue to do it！You know it！
她过去骗你，现在骗你，将来还会骗你的！
It's me，Josh！
救我啊，我是约什
Please don't let me die！Please don't let me die！Don't kill me！
不不！求你了！别让我死！别杀我！
Fuck
操！
Oh，God！
佛祖啊！
Thank you！
谢谢！
Oh，well that's it，isn't it？！It's over！
好啊，原来是这么回事！这就结束了是吧！
- You motherfucker！- Stop it…
- 你这王八蛋！ - 不要…
You spineless，pussy- whipped MOTHERFUCKER！
你这见色忘义的大烧饼！我操你妈个B！
That's all it takes，huh？！A bitch says one thing and it's all over！
就这么着了是吧！这2个骚货瞎吹都信！
You know what，William？Your policy，it's bullshit！
知道吗！屎盾！你的那些理论，都是狗屎！！
Fucking bullshit！
都是大便！！！
Well，you listen to me，you son of a bitch！
你个逼养给劳资听着
I did everything for you.
劳资为你做牛做马！
Look at me！When you're killing me，you look at me！
抬起头来！！敢做不敢当么！！
Thank you.
谢谢你…
Oh，my God！
上帝啊
- Thank you。- Emily.
- 谢谢你… - 爱米粒…
Right now，you're feeling helpless.
感到很无助吧
- How's it going？- Good.
- 进展如何？ - 挺顺利
This is it.
就这儿
Whoever made this tape had access to
这盘录像带的制作者使用的是
some very impressive audio filtration equipment.
一套极其高端的音频绿坝设备
Right now，you're feeling helpless.
感到很无助吧
Fortunately，we have some tricks of our own，here.
幸好我们有相关对策
I can turn his algorithm upside- down and let us hear what he really sounds like.
我可以倒置他的程序，如此逐步解出原声
Let's hear what you got.
让我们听听当前破解出的
Right now，you're feeling helpless.
感到很无助吧
- You okay？- Huh？
- 你没事吧？ - 啊？
You seem a little preoccupied.
貌似有点心神不宁？
I'm just anxious about the tape.
我只是急着想听到声音
Right now，you're feeling helpless.
感到很无助吧
- Right now，you're feeling helpless。- You know，there are still a couple of things
- 感到很无助吧 - 晓得伐，我还有很多事情
- I can't quite wrap my head around。- Right now，you're feeling helpless.
- 没整明白 - 感到很无助吧
Like，I don't understand Strahm's motivation.
比如，小斯的动机是什么？
He was my partner for five years.
我和他搭档5年了
I mean，we all knew he was a bit of a hothead
我们都知道他是个急性子
but I never saw any indication of psychotic behavior.
可是从他身上看不出任何变态行为的迹象
You can't really tell when someone's so good on the inside.
虎豹不堪骑，人心隔肚皮
…helpless.
…无助
- Hear that？- Right now，you're feeling helpless.
- 听见没？ - 感到很无助吧
I'm getting there.
就快出来了
Come on。I thought you had something to show us.
加油，我就知道你一定行
It's just I never really thought of him being vengeful.
我从没想过他是报复心这么重的人
- Right now，you're feeling helpless。- You know？I mean，all the facts are there.
- 感到很无助吧 - 我的意思是，所有事实摆在这证明一点：
- But something doesn't sit right。- Listen。It's getting closer.
- 事情有点不大对劲 - 听！很接近了
- Right now，you're feeling… - You know，there is an alternative.
- 现在感到… - 你看有没有这种可能性
Let's say that Strahm killed Seth Baxter
小斯杀塞斯·巴克斯特是为了嫁祸给你
specifically to set you up as an accomplice to Jigsaw.
让我们误以为你是老头的新门徒
Okay.
有这可能
Well，there's a problem with that，though.
但是，这里有个问题
On further analysis of Strahm's fingerprints，
经过对小斯指纹的进一步分析
it was found that the uric acid levels in the eccrine gland residue
发现其尿酸水平
were inconsistent for an individual with an active epidermal metabolism.
与一个拥有正常硬膜代谢的人不相符
In other words？
言下之意？
In other words，when he left his fingerprints on the latest victim，
也就是说，小斯留下那些指纹之前
Strahm was already dead.
就已经死了！
- Right now，you're feeling helpless。- There it is.
- 现在，感到很无助吧 - 出来了！
Right now，you're feeling helpless.
现在，感到很无助吧
Who else knows about me？
还有谁知道这事！
Who else fucking knows about me？
说！还有谁！
- Everyone。- You lie。You're fucking lying.
- 人尽皆知！ - 你这骗子！你这个该死的大骗子！
I found something you'll want to see.
我找到了一样你一定很想看到的东西
It was at the location where John died.
就在约翰死的那个肉厂
Does it mean anything to you？
怎么样，有帮助吧？
What are you doing？
你在干嘛？
Get as far away from the sprinkler head as possible.
离那玩意儿远点！
We don't know what it does！
我们还没弄清楚状况
I'm not gonna just sit here and do nothing.
不能光这么坐着，要做点什么！
We need to make a decision！Don't you understand？
我们要做个决定！您明不明啊！
Okay。You can pull it。I love you.
好吧，你推吧，妈妈爱你
I love you，too。Get back.
我也爱您，退后
No。You don't know what it does
不要！你们不知道会发生什么！
- On three，I「II pull it。- Okay.
- 数到三，我就推 - 行
No。No.
不！不要啊！
One，
一，
two，
二，
three！
三！
What the fuck？
怎么回事？
It doesn't even work！It doesn't even fucking work！
怎么拉了没效果？？为什么拉了没用！
What the fuck？
妈的这算什么！
It doesn't make any fucking sense.
不能够啊…
I think I know what it does.
我想我知道怎么用了
Get used to me，'cause I'm not going anywhere.
你得习惯我在这唠叨，因为我哪也不会去
You sure about that？
你真这么认为么？
Amanda will fail you.
阿曼达会辜负你
We'll see.
我们拭目以待
「Amanda，you were with Cecil the night Jill lost Gideon.」
“阿曼达，吉儿流产那晚你和西塞在一起
Go.
去吧
- What the fuck are you doing？Go。Go。- I don't know about this.
- 你还墨迹什么玩意儿？去啊！快去！ - 我不知道我…
- What do you mean，you don't know？- She's been good to us.
- 什么玩意儿你不知道？ - 她对我们挺好的
I've been good to you.
我对你不好吗？
- I know… - Please，please，go.
- 我知道… - 求你了，求求你，去吧
You drive me crazy.
疯了你
Go on，you fucking pussy！Go！Go！Go！
快去啊！没用的东西！快点！快点！快！
- Cecil！No！- Listen to me！
- 西塞！不要！ - 听我说！
「You killed their child.
“是你害死了他们的孩子”
「You know it and I know it，so do exactly as I say.
“这事你知，我也知，所以你要按我说的去做”
「Kill Lynn Denlon or I will tell John what you did.」
“杀了莲恩·戴伦，不然我就把真相告诉门主”
She doesn't deserve to go free！
这贱货根本不配活命！
Amanda，Lynn is more important than you know.
阿曼达，莲医生比你想像得要重要
Lynn！
莲恩！
I made it。I made it。I made it！
我成功了！我做到了！我通关了！
If you fail，you will never see your family again.
否则，你将再也见不到你的家人
- What are you doing here？- Will！
- 你们在这干嘛？ - 威廉！
Pamela！
帕梅拉！
I know it's your birthday.I'm going to make it up to you，I promise.
我知道今个是你生日，我会补的，放心
Are you really standing up your sister for work？I'm your only family.
你的那份工作和你唯一的妹妹到底哪个重要？
- Are you all right？- Yeah.
- 你没事吧？ - 恩
Let her go！I mean it！I won！
放她走！我通关了！我赢了！
I followed your fucking rules！Now you let her go！
你那狗P规则我都遵守了，放她出去！！
You son of a bitch！
你这挨千刀的
You've just given me a death sentence.I mean，who's going to cover me now？
这代价我怎么担得起？你等于判了我死刑
You just killed me.
白眼狼
Come on，let's go.
走吧，咱们走
You're the man that killed my dad.
你就是杀我爸爸的凶手
Hello，Tara。My apologies for exposing you and your son to this kind of treatment.
你好，塔拉，很抱歉把你和你儿子卷进这款游戏中
But I can assure you，it is not without reason.
但这里边是有原因的
The man before you just made the sacrifices to save the life of a loved one.
这个男人进来之前为救他人，牺牲自我
However，when given the opportunity to save your husband's life，
然而，他原本有机会救你的丈夫
he chose not to.
但他没有
Now you will be given the power to save a life.
现在我给你一个权力
Will you grant this man the opportunity to continue living？
来决定一个人的命运
Or will you dispense the same death sentence
你是愿意给仇人改过自新的机会
he issued your husband？
还是选择像当初仇人对你丈夫那样，宣判他的死刑？
Live or die.
是生，是死
The choice is yours.
决定权在于你
It's not my game.
原来这不是我的游戏…
I'm leaving you a box today，and its contents are of grave importance.
我留了个宝箱给你，里面的东西至关重要
Miss Tuck，what's in the box？
塔克夫人，里面是什么？
Please。Please forgive me.
求你了，求你原谅我
Have mercy，please！
求求你，发发慈悲吧
Did he show mercy when my husband was suffering？
我丈夫遭受病魔折磨的时候他的慈悲在哪！
John left you five envelopes.
约翰留给你五个信封
The sixth one was for me.
但第六个是给我的
This is John's will.
这是他的遗愿
…to watch this horror！
观看这次恐惧！
- He had no choice！- He always had a choice！
- 他没办法… - 他当然有办法！
The reason I am doing this isn't because I can't forgive you
为什么我非得这么做？不是因为我不能原谅
for what you did to me.
你对我家所做的罪行
The reason I'm doing this
而是因为
is because I couldn't forgive myself for what you might do to someone else.
我不能忍受像你这种人在外头胡作非为！
Please，no。Please.
不…千万不要啊！
- You will never kill again。- Please.
- 你再也害不了人了！ - 求求你
Please.
求你不要
求求你
Please.
Please。Please.
求你了！求求你了！
I can't。I can't kill him.
不成…我下不了手…
But I can.
我来！
- No，Brent！- You killed my father，you motherfucker！
- 不，布伦特！ - 你杀了我爸，你个小逼养！
Now you burn in hell.
下地狱去吧！
Game over.
游戏结束
- John Kramer。- William Easton.
- 约翰·克莱默 - 威廉·伊斯盾
Nice to meet you.
很高兴见到你
- Those are the rules，Harold。- You've just given me a death sentence.
- 我是按规矩办事，哈罗德 - 你等于判了我死刑
So，in a sense，you choose who lives or dies.
这么说来在某种程度上你能选择谁生谁死
No！
不！！
It's policy，John。It's policy.
这是国家政策，老翰，是政策
You think it's the living who will have ultimate judgment over you，
你以为只有活人才能对你终审
because the dead will have no claim over your soul，
而死人是没有怨言的
but you may be mistaken.
你错了
So when's your test，Detective？
你什么时候玩游戏啊？警官
- I don't need one。- Oh，yeah？
- 我不需要玩 - 哦？是吗？
You know why you're here，don't you？
应该晓得为什么你会在这吧？嗯？
I want to know if you have what it takes to survive.
我想知道你是否有资格活下来
You feel you now have control，don't you？
你觉得可以掌控局势了是吗？
You think you will walk away untested.
你以为不经过考验就太平了？
Do you like how brutality feels，Mark？
你就那么崇尚暴力吗？马克
I'm only carrying out John's final request.
我只是在了结约翰最后的遗愿
You want a chance？I'll give you a chance.
想要机会吗？我来给你一个机会
Remember…
记住
Don't trust the one who saves you.
不要相信那个来救你的人